A Guide to the Marion Dillon George and David Pelham George Papers, 1993-2019
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Marion Dillon George and David Pelham George, 1993-2019
The Library of Virginia
52619
13.45 cu. ft. (26 boxes)
Marion Dillon George and David Pelham George
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Marion Dillon George.
Biographical Information
Marion Dillon George (1942-) and David Pelham George (1932-2014) were both native Virginians who, after their 1981 marriage, became increasingly interested in their families' histories and genealogies. Marion George (nee Dillon) obtained a bachelor's degree from Mary Washington College and a master's degree from the University of North Carolina, and worked as a corporate librarian at the United Virginia bank in Richmond before being promoted to a Vice President. David George attended the University of Richmond and worked as a sales representative in Winston-Salem, North Carolina, before returning to Richmond to pursue a career at the Reynolds Metal, Co, where he worked until his retirement in 1993. The couple were active in a number of genealogical and historical societies and were members of Sons of the American Revolution, Sons of Confederate Veterans, Daughters of the American Revolution, and Dames of Colonial Cavaliers, among others. David Pelham George died in 2014, and was survived by his wife Marion, his son David Pelham George, Jr., and his daughter Belinda Sue George. Marion Dillion George currently lives in Richmond, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1993-2019, of Marion Dillon George and David Pelham George consist of their research on the George and Dillon families and associated lines. Collection contains correspondence, notes, vital records, family trees, and genealogical charts, and includes information on lines which settled in numerous Virginia counties including Amelia, Caroline, Chesterfield, Cumberland, Franklin, Frederick, Goochland, Hanover, Henrico, and Louisa, as well as Kentucky, Missouri, Washington, North Carolina, Tennessee, and West Virginia. Collection also contains applications, newsletters, directories, and certificates from historical and genealogical societies, and details their family lineage from pre-colonial America.
Contents List
- George Genealogy Direct Line Notebook, 1820-2004 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- George Genealogy Direct Line Notebook, 1850-2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- George Genealogy North Carolina Notebook, 1790-1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- George Genealogy North Carolina Notebook, 1790-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- George Genealogy North Carolina Notebook, 1790-2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bondurants in Print Notebook, 1980 and 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Bondurant Family Newsletters Notebook 2013-2015 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Bondurant Family Newsletters Notebook 2008-2011 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Bondurant Family Newsletters Notebook 2006-2008 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Bondurant Census Notebook, 1790-1910 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Bondurant Genealogy A-L Notebook, 1832-2006 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Bondurant Genealogy A-L Notebook, 1734-2004 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Bondurant Genealogy A-L Notebook, 1790-2004 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Bondurant Genealogy M-Z Notebook, 1807-2004 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Bondurant Genealogy M-Z Notebook, 1792-2004 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Moseley Genealogy Notebook, 1605-2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Moseley Genealogy Notebook, 1812-1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Moseley Genealogy Notebook, 1746-1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Moseley Genealogy Notebook, 1729-2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Moseley Genealogy Notebook, ca. 1600-1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Moseley Genealogy Notebook, 1677-1810 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Buckingham General Genealogy Notebook, 1771-1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Hooper Genealogy Notebook, 1782-2000 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Hooper Genealogy Notebook, 1775-1996 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Hooper Genealogy Notebook, 1761-1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Hooper Genealogy Notebook, 1810-1999 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Gilliam Genealogy Notebook, 1837-2010 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Gilliam Genealogy Notebook, 1789-2004 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Gilliam Genealogy Notebook, 1794-1998 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Gilliam Genealogy Notebook, 1840-1998 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Dillon A-M Genealogy Notebook, 1810-2009 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Dillon A-M Genealogy Notebook, ca. 1782-1900 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Dillon A-M Genealogy Notebook, 1779-1998 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Dillon N-Z Genealogy Notebook, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Dillon N-Z Genealogy Notebook, 1758-1949 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Dillon N-Z Genealogy Notebook, 1786-1978 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous Hooper Papers 1797-2014 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Mason Genealogy Notebook, 1720-2001 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Mason Genealogy Notebook, ca. 1637-2000 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Mason Genealogy Notebook, 1762-2000 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Hamilton and Monteith Genealogy Notebook, ca. 1724-2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Cox Genealogy Notebook, 1752-1936 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Cox Genealogy Notebook, ca. 1724-2001 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Bocock Genealogy Notebook, 1784-2008 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Mabe (Maib, Maibe) Genealogy Notebook, 1738-2008 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Military Service Notebook, 1863-1865 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Virginia Census Indices Notebook, 1720-1998 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Marriages by Fisher Notebook, 1851-1990 and 1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Marriages by Fisher Notebook, 1851-1900 and 1994 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Marriages by Fisher Notebook, 1722-1850 and 1990 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- "Few First Families of Virginia" by Holman Notebook, ca. 1609-1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- "Few First Families of Virginia" by Holman Notebook, ca. 1630-1969 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Military Service Genealogy Notebook, 1861-1865 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Military Service Genealogy Notebook, 1820-1999 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Shelton Genealogy Notebook, 1798-2001 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Shelton Genealogy Notebook, 1809-2001 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Shelton Direct Line Notebook, 1724-2011 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Shelton Direct Line Notebook, 1823-2013 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Shelton Direct Line Notebook, 1789-2014 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Shelton Genealogy Publications Notebook, 1228-1981 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Shelton Genealogy Publications Notebook, 1215-1978 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Grigsby Genealogy Notebook, 1727-2004 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Grigsby Genealogy Notebook, 1624-2004 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Military Service Folder, 1861-2001 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Military Service Folder, 1776-2004 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Cox General Data Folder, 1607-1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Fredericksburg, VA Research Resources Folder, 1888-1889 and 2000 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Bondurant Folder, 1830-2004 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Bondurant Folder, 1841-2004 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Bondurant Folder, 1810-2004 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Bondurant Folder, 1790-2004 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Bondurant Folder, 1766-2004 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Bondurant Folder, 1734-2008 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Bondurant Folder, 1709-2004 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Bondurant Miscellaneous Folder, 1728-2004 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Joel Bondurant (Later One + Family) Folder, ca. 1860's-1920's (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Bondurant Working File, 1708-2012 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Bondurant Working File, ca. 1700-2010 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- SAR Application Materials, ca. 1825-2001 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- SAR Application Materials, ca. 1825-2006 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Mason Folder, 1765-1956 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Mason Folder, 1806-2001 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Mason Folder, 1773-1999 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Mason Folder, 1695-2001 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Mason Folder, 1765-2001 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Mason et. al Folder, 1720-2001 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Mason et. al Folder, 1763-2004 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Mason et. al Folder, 1745-2001 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Mason et. al Folder, 1765-2001 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Mason et. al Folder, 1750-2001 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Mason- Important Papers Folder, 1763-2011 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- NC Census Data-George Folder, 1720-2011 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- NC Census Data-George Folder, 1800-2008 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- George Land Folder, 1745-2004 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- George- North Carolina Folder, 1761-2014 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- George Folder, 1741-2004 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- George Tombstones Photographs, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Humphreys and Littreal Folder, 1710-2004 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Humphreys and Littreal Folder, 1830-2005 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Shelton Folder, 1725-2001 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Shelton Folder, 1724-2002 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Shelton Folder, 1770-2004 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Shelton Folder, 1724-2014 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Shelton Folder, 1720-2001 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Shelton Tombstones Photographs, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Notes D+M Folder, 1764-1880 and undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Correspondence Folder, 2012 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Gilliam Bible Records Folder, 1759-1998 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Gilliam Births Folder, 1853-1866 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Gilliam Marriages Folder, ca. 1754-1998 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Gilliam Census Records Folder, 1771-2004 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Gilliam Confederate Records Folder, 1844-1865 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Gilliam-General Folder, ca. 1660-2000 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Gilliam Homes Folder, 1769-2013 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Gilliam Land Sales Folder, 1762-2004 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Gilliam Public Service Claims Folder, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Secondary Historical Source Material Folder, 1773-1998 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Buckingham Folder, 1827-2014 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Buckingham Folder, 1771-2013 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Buckingham-General Folder, 1788-2007 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Buckingham-General Folder, 1800-1999 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Buckingham Maps Folder, 1967-1991 and undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Maysville Church Records Folder, 1833-1946 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Maysville Church Records Folder, 1845-1997 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Misc. Data-Other Folder, 1807-1997 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- New Store Baptist Church Folder, 1890-1996 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Cumberland General Data Folder, 1800 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Cumberland County Historical Bulletin, 1986-1996 (Box 14, Folder 12)
- Gilliam-War of 1812 Folder, 1851 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Watkins Family Folder, 1736-1989 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Richardson Folder, 1821-1986 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Rives Family Folder, 1768-1986 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Dillon-Miscellaneous Folder, 1749-1999 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- West Virginia Miscellaneous Folder, ca. 1821-1977 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Dillon-Confederates Folder, 1838-1988 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Dillon Important Photocopies Folder, 1737-2004 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Dillon-National Personnel Records Center Folder, 1942-2002 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Dillon-Miscellaneous Folder, 1774-2008 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Dillon-Miscellaneous Folder, 1744-1999 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Dillon-Miscellaneous Folder, 1763-1996 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Dillon-Miscellaneous Folder, 1905-2002 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Dillon-National Library of Ireland Folder, 1893-1996 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Nannie's Newspaper Clippings Folder, 1962-2017 and undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Jamestowne Society Application Folder, 1627-2007 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Jamestowne Society Newsletters Folder, 2004-2014 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Jamestowne Society Newsletters Folder, 2004-2009 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Jamestowne Society Newsletters Folder, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Daughters of American Colonists Folder, 1994-2009 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Vital Records-Originals Folder 1905-2001 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Marion's Family Tree Folder, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Nannie Gilliam Dillon Folder, 1911-2007 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Gilliam-Wakeham Vital/Legal Records Folder, 1768-2004 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Originals Folder, 1823-1939 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- D.A.R. Supplements Folder, 1724-2004 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Arthur Allen Folder, 1897-1900 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- D.A.R Supp.-Chambers Family Folder, 1777-2004 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- D.A.R Supp.-M. Cox Folder, 1710-2004 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- D.A.R Supp.-J. Watson Folder, 1720-2004 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Allen, James/Benjamin Folder, 1724-2004 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Branch Family Folder, 1602-2004 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Bridger Family Folder, 1628-2007 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Cocke and Bailey Family Folder, ca. 1600-2004 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Cooke Family Folder, ca. 1700-2004 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Curd Family Folder, 1743-2004 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Farley Folder, ca. 1600-1943 (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Davis Folder, ca. 1775-2004 (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Hancock Family Folder, ca. 1650-2004 (Box 17, Folder 14)
- Harris Family Folder, ca. 1586-2008 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Harris Family Folder, ca. 1582-1868 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Harris Family Folder, ca. 1634-1968 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Harris Family Folder, ca. 1583-2004 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Ligon Family Folder, ca. 1611-2004 (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Ligon Family Folder, 1611-1995 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Moseley, Robert (Husband of Magdalen Guerrant) Folder, 1732-2002 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Pitt, Robert Folder, ca. 1605-2004 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Richardson Family Folder, 1653-2004 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Robertson Folder, ca. 1625-2004 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Tinsley Family Folder, ca. 1645-2004 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Williamson Family Folder, ca. 1593-2004 (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Wooldridge Folder, 1678-2004 (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Public Service Claims Folder, 1781-1783 and undated (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Births Folder, 1855-1896 (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Marriage Records Folder, 1796-2004 (Box 18, Folder 16)
- Deaths Folder, 1831-2006 (Box 19, Folder 1)
- Hooper-Misc. Folder, 1732-2006 (Box 19, Folder 2)
- Hooper-Misc. Folder, 1632-2005 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Wills-Hooper Folder, 1751-1998 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- War of 1812 Service Records Folder, 1809-2012 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Land Patents, Grants, Plats, Tax Folder, 1760-1997 (Box 19, Folder 6)
- Land Patents, Grants, Plats, Tax Folder, ca. 1664-1999 (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Original Documents Folder, ca. 1736-2001 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Original Documents Folder, 1771-2005 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Confederate Military Service Folder, 1814-2014 (Box 20, Folder 1)
- Hooper Census Data, 1850-1870 (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Homes-Hooper Folder, ca. 1800-2001 (Box 20, Folder 3)
- Tax Records-Land Folder, 1782-1998 (Box 20, Folder 4)
- Tax Records-Property Folder, 1763-1987 (Box 20, Folder 5)
- Chancery Files Folder, 1869-1907 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- Hoopers in England Folder, 1562-2003 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- Pictures Folder, 1913-2007 and undated (Box 20, Folder 8)
- Pictures Folder, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
- Wills- Marion's Family Folder, 1937-1981 (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Descendancy Charts Folder, ca. 1736-1997 (Box 20, Folder 11)
- Johns Folder, ca. 1715-2014 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Johns Folder, ca. 1737-2011 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Moseley Folder, ca. 1606-1990 (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Moseley Folder, 1793-2011 (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Dames of Colonial Cavaliers Folder, ca. 1606-2007 (Box 21, Folder 5)
- Dames of Colonial Cavaliers Folder, ca. 1606-2005 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Dames of Colonial Cavaliers Folder, 2002-2018 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- D.A.R. Application Folder, ca. 1688-2009 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- D.A.R. Newsletters and Directories Folder, 2003-2014 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- D.A.R. Newsletters and Directories Folder, 2014-2017 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- Historic Buckingham Newsletters Folder, 2006-2017 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Historic Buckingham Newsletters Folder, 1995-2005 (Box 22, Folder 4)
- Descendants of Ancient Planters Application Folder, ca. 1721-2002 (Box 22, Folder 5)
- Descendants of Ancient Planters Directories Folder, 2002-2008 (Box 22, Folder 6)
- Descendants of Ancient Planters Directories Folder, 2009-2018 (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Descendants of Ancient Planters Newsletters Folder, 2002-2017 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Daughters of 1812 Application Folder, 1773-2001 (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Daughters of 1812 Newsletters and Directories Folder, 1997-2009 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Daughters of 1812 Newsletters and Directories Folder, 2016-2017 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Huguenot Society- Newsletters and Directors Folder, 2004-2017 (Box 23, Folder 3)
- Huguenot Society- Newsletters and Directors Folder, 2004-2014 (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Huguenot Society Application Folder, 1663-2004 (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Colonial Dames of America Folder, 2002-2019 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Colonial Dames of America Folder, 2016-2017 (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Colonial Dames of America Folder, 1997-2017 (Box 24, Folder 1)
- Colonial Dames Application Folder, ca. 1605-2005 (Box 24, Folder 2)
- Virginia Society Sons of the American Revolution Certificates, 2001 and 2009 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- United Daughters of the Confederacy Certificate, 1999 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- National Society Unitd States Daughters of 1812 Certificate, 2001 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Order of the Descendants of American Planters Certificates, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Jamestowne Society Certificate, 2002 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- National Society of Daughters of the American Colonists Certificate, 2000 (Box 24, Folder 8)
- National Society of Daughters of the American Revolution Certificate, 1999 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- National Soceity of the Colonial Dames of America Certificates, 2002 and 2005 (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Sons of Confederate Veterans Certificate, 1999 and 2003 (Box 24, Folder 11)
- National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution Certificates 2003-2004 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- The Grand Lodge of North Carolina Certificate, 2007 (Box 24, Folder 13)
- Rapahanoc Yearbook, Volume 2, 1922 (Box 24, Folder 14)
- Grafton-Shelton Marriage License, 1930 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- The Huguenot Society of the Founders of Manakin in the Colony of Virginia Certificate, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Dames of Colonial Cavaliers Certificate, 2002 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- National Society of the United States Daughters of 1812 Certificate, 1999 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- E.F. Houghton, 1865-1965 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Grand Lodge Service Award, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Paul Jon Miller Award, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)